murdoch.edu.au 2004-12-27

# Murdoch University University Web Sites Privacy Notice

The following sets out how Murdoch University will deal with personal information related to the content and use of its Web sites.

  1. Information Collected
  2. Use of Personal Information
  3. Disclosure of Personal Information
  4. Data Quality / Access
  5. Complaints and Queries About Privacy
  6. University Privacy Policy

## 1\. Information Collected

### Information automatically logged

The University may make a record of your visit and log any of the following information: 

  * the user's Server address
  * the user's domain name (eg. .edu, .gov, .com, .au, .uk, etc)
  * IP address
  * the date and time of the visit to a site
  * the pages accessed and documents downloaded
  * the previous site visited
  * the type of browser used

The data collected is used for the following purposes: 

  * Web site and system administration, including monitoring to prevent security breaches
  * enhancement of Web sites to better meet user needs
  * research and development

Identification of the user may also be requested and logged. 

If you are not a Murdoch student or a University staff member and you send us a message, the University will record your e-mail address.

### Security Information

University Web sites have security measures in place against the loss, misuse and alteration of information as defined in the [University's IT Security Policy](http://wwwits2.murdoch.edu.au/security/policy.html).

Secure sites require users to identify themselves. For example a user may be prompted at a login screen to enter a Murdoch Username and Murdoch Password. The University also uses Secure Servers with digital IDs when providing users with access to information that is personal, sensitive or confidential (eg. assessment results). 

### Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of information given to your Web browser by our Web Server. The browser stores the message in a text file and the message is then sent back to the Web Sserver each time the browser requests a page from the Server. It is possible to disable the acceptance of cookies by your Web browser. However, doing so may restrict your ability to access some Web pages.

Some University Web sites are access restricted. These sites may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interest. Cookies may also be used for authentication purposes and to improve security during a visitor's session online.

Cookies may store the following information: session (numbered key) and duration. A numbered key is a unique Server generated number used to track your current session. The session key can be linked back to a user's login identification.

Unique identifiers (such as login username and password) are collected from visitors to our Web sites to verify a user's identity.

Unique identifiers may also be used to access stored information about a visitor's preferences to enable the dynamic display of the site according to your preferences when you return.

###  Online Surveys

All research surveys conducted online by University staff and /or students which involve the collection of personal information, will have received approval from the University's [Human Research Ethics Committee](http://www.research.murdoch.edu.au/ethics/hrec/hrec.asp). A survey might ask visitors for unique identifiers (such as login information).

Exceptions that do not require approval are: 

  1. Evaluation activities carried out as part of the normal course of education such as student surveys conducted by the Institutional Research and Evaluation Service (IRES) and 
  2. Historical research projects that involve investigation using publicly available records. 

### Enrolment and Registration forms

If personal information is collected via a Web site and held, every effort will be made to ensure that this is done by sufficiently secure means. 

The University uses Secure Servers (digital ID) to encrypt data exchanged between Web browser and Web Server. Information such as addresses, enrolment details and assessment results are accessed via a Secure Server. 

For certain applications, our site's enrolment and/ registration forms require users to give contact information (like name and email address) and unique identifiers (like login identification and student ID number).

### External Links

Content hosted on University sites may contain links to other Internet accessible sites. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

## 2\. Use of Personal Information

Personal information you supply online will be used by the University staff in conducting the business of the University. Such uses include matters related to student administration, provision of services and the dissemination of information to staff, prospective and current students and remaining in contact with graduates. The University may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with a server and to administer a Web site. Your IP address is sometimes used to set up individual sessions to provide secure logins.

## 3\. Disclosure of Personal Information

Staff email addresses, room numbers and phone numbers are made available within the Campus Directory. Staff may elect to not have their email address displayed.

With respect to information about students, all information about identifiable individual students is confidential, and will not be disclosed to third parties unless: 

  * the student has authorised its release; or 
  * the university is required by legislation, court order, or other legally enforceable instrument to provide the information to a government agency or to another individual, and the request is in an appropriate written format; or
  * disclosure is reasonably believed to be necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to the life or health of the student, or of another person. 

The University does not release results, enrolment details, addresses or telephone numbers to third parties (even parents, employers and police) except in accordance with the above principles. 

The only information which the University will freely provide to third parties is to confirm: 

  * whether or not a person with a particular name is currently enrolled at the university, or has ever been a student of the university; and 
  * whether the person is a Murdoch graduate, and, if so, year of graduation, degree, course and, if applicable, class of honours - all of these details are already on the public record, as they are attached to the Academic Council minutes and most appear in the Degree Ceremony programme.

The University provides enrolment and assessment information to several organisations where this is required under legislation, or where students have authorised this release as a condition of their sponsorship or application for assistance or employment. 

### Public Forums

Some University sites may have chat rooms, forums, online teaching environments, message boards and or/news groups available to their users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

## 4\. Data Quality/Access

The University will always try to maintain accurate, complete and up-to-date information regarding staff and students. If you think that your personal information retained by the University requires changing, please use MyInfo (students) and change the details online, or contact your Division. Staff may use MyInfo (staff) to change their contact address details and the Personal Details Editor to change their email address displayed in the Campus Directory. This editor may also be used to request Human Resources to change name details. 

## 5\. Complaints and Queries About Privacy

Any user with a query or complaint relating to online privacy issues with respect to Content hosted on or accessed via Murdoch University Web Servers, may either contact staff responsible for administration of MurdochNet, or [Andrew Bain](mailto:a.bain@murdoch.edu.au), the University Secretary. 

## 6\. University Privacy Policy

This notice should be read in conjunction with the University's Privacy Policy. 

* * *

This notice has been adapted from the [Monash University's Web Site Privacy Statement](http://www.monash.edu.au/legals/privacy.html).
